Zaw Myo Latt

Back-end Developer

Address – Blk 93, #04-3037, Paya Lebar Road, Singapore 370093.

Mobile – +6587847812, Email – <u>zawmyolatt.ucsy@gmail.com</u>

Linkedin – https://www.linkedin.com/in/zaw-myo-latt-57449979

Skype – zawmyolatt1122

Summary

My name is Zaw Myo Latt.Graduated from the University of Computer Studies, Yangon (UCSY) in Myanmar and got a Bachelor of Science in Computer Information and Technology (B.C.Sc). Experiences and knowledge obtained through university life and work experiences. After graduating from university, I have an interest in the web application area. That's why I worked as a web developer for over 1 year. Then, I was promoted as a Team Leader at the same company iKloudit Myanmar Office (iKloudit is a Singapore Company), locally called Ever Crystal One-stop IT Solution. There, we have to write the web app projects, which were sold in our Singapore Head Office such as HR System, POS System, CMS and other E-commerce System etc,.

Then after 3 years, I joined <u>GMBF Group of Companies</u> (which was founded myanmar) as an IT Manager.In GMBF, i took the responsibility of project management, task management, mobile apps and web apps development like Bus Ticket Booking system, Coupon based marketing development system etc. After 2 years later, I moved to Singapore at 2019 and joined as **Back-End Developer** in <u>Carpal Fleet</u>. During the covid period, Carpal shutdown their business around June 2020, then I joined <u>GovTech(Notarise</u>) team and worked as a full stack developer there for 1 and half year. Then, I got an offer from <u>Grab</u> DigiBank Team around August 2022 and working as a Software Engineer, Backend till today.

Graduated Date: May 2013

Educational Background

Bachelor's Degree of Computer Science/Information Technology

Major: Software Engineering

Institute/University: University of Computer Studies, Yangon, Myanmar

Current Specialization: Web Technology - Web Application - Back-end Services

Honors and Certificates

2010-2011 - Durosoft Web Studio, Certified in advanced PHP (Now Fairway web)

2011-2012 - Certified in Practical Network Course

- Certified the Excellence in IT Business Plan Contest 2013(ICCNA)

- Winner team of Contest on Technopreneurship 2014

(Conducted by Myanmar-Korea IT Center)

Personal Particulars & Preferences

Date of Birth: 12 Jan 1993

Nationality: Myanmar

Skills Summary

- Web Technologies & Frameworks: Go, Go-Kit, Angular, Vue, Ionic, Nodejs, Serverless,
 PHP, Python, Laravel, Yii, Code Igniter, Django, Aws Services, chalice Serverless, Lambda,
 SNS, SQS etc.
- Scripts/UI: JavaScript, Typescript, BootStrap, React, Tailwind
- Database and ORM: MySQL, SQL, Dynamodb, Elasticsearch, sqlite, Pgsql
- Application/Web Server: Apache, Nginx, Expressjs, Nodejs, Serverless
- Versioning and other tools: Git, GitLab, Bitbucket, Jira, Pivotal Tracker etc.
- Deployment Tools: Docker, k8s, Vagrant, CI/CD setup, helm, terraform, Laravel Forge

Experiences

iKloudit (Web Developer)



Oct 2013 - 2015

- Developed web applications by using PHP framework like code igniter/ laravel, etc
- Most of the applications which I developed are POS System, Invoicing System, HR System and LMS System etc.



Ever Crystal (Team Lead)

Oct 2015 - 2018

- Developed web api services and also did integration with some kind of api interface like rest, soap.
- Also develop hybrid mobile application by using ionic1 and angular1,cordova etc
- Most of the applications which I developed are Reward System, HR System and Ecommerce System etc.

GMBF Group of Companies (IT Manager)



Nov 2018 - Dec 2019

- Did cloud server management, CI/CD and git branching strategy
- Also develop hybrid mobile application by using ionic 3/4 and angular 6/7, cordova etc
- Most of the applications which we developed are Reward System, HR System, Ecommerce System, Bus Ticketing System and other travel & tour related systems.

<u>Carpal Fleet</u> (Back-End Developer)



Jan 2019 - Jun 2020

- Developing web application fleet api by using mainly laravel (PHP) for solving vehicle routing and allocating the order driver efficient and effectively
- For the storage we use mainly mysql and also use some AWS services like s3, dynamodb and elasticsearch for indexing data
- used pub/sub messaging architecture for validating, dispatch & allocate orders by using AWS Lambda and SNS etc..
- Writing unit tests and setup pipeline for CI/CD using docker
- Developing some user analytic script and micro services are using python and Chalice(python framework)<u>Carpal Fleet</u> (Back-End Developer)



GovTech (Software Specialist, CSG Team)

Oct 2020 - Mar 2021

- Maintaining and implementing new features in internal Django web applications under CSG.
- Have experience with rabbitmq for queuing tasks using celery and also wrote some api calls for <u>Nexpose</u>.
- Writing unit tests for django Application and setup CI/CD integration in private gitlab.



GovTech (Software Specialist, Notarise Team)

April 2021 - July 2022

- Maintaining and implementing new features in <u>Notarise</u> application.
- Have experience with serverless APIs, nodejs, react etc.. and learn how to set up securely
- Take ownership for some vaccine digital certification APIs and develop some new features as per request.



Grab (Software Engineer (Backend), DigiBank Team)

August 2022 - Present

- Maintaining and implementing new features in digibank Backend services.
- Have experience with Go, terraform, helm, k8s etc and also learning to set up services securely
- Take ownership for some part of the fintrust & AML related APIs and develop some new features as per request.

Languages

Language	Spoken	Written
Burmese	Native	Native
English	Intermediate	Advance
Tamil	Beginner	-

Communication Skill

I worked together with the Singapore Marketing Team to communicate on Skype, since 2014 when I worked at ikloudit. And also in previous companies, I worked together with some foreign scrum master, product managing guys as remote. So, I am able to communicate effectively with a wide range of people, by showing interest and carefully listening to their needs. Strong presentation and demonstrating skills; Confident, articulate and professional speaking abilities.